paydq.com 2008-09-29

# PAYDQ - Privacy Statement

Updated September 26, 2007. **PAY DQ** is committed to protecting your privacy and the privacy of your customers. Please note, this privacy statement pertains to this web site only

**Collection of your Personal Information**  
We will ask you when we need information that personally identifies you (personal information) or allows us to contact you to provide a service or carry out a transaction that you have requested such as receiving information about **PAY DQ** products and services, ordering e-mail newsletters, joining a limited-access service, signing up for an event or training, or when purchasing, downloading and/or registering **PAY DQ** products. The personal information we collect may include your name, title, company or organization name, work e-mail, work phone, work or home address, information about your job function, and information about your company.

The Site may collect certain information about your visit, such as the name of the Internet service provider and the Internet Protocol (IP) address through which you access the Internet; the date and time you access the Site; the pages that you access while at the Site and the Internet address of the Web site from which you linked directly to our site. This information is used to help improve the Site, analyze trends, and administer the Site. Top of page

**Use of Your Personal Information**  
The personal information collected on this Site will be used to operate the Site and to provide the service(s) or carry out the transaction(s) you have requested or authorized.

In support of these uses, **PAY DQ** may use personal information to provide you with more effective customer service, to improve the Site and any related **PAY DQ** products or services, and to make the Site easier to use by eliminating the need for you to repeatedly enter the same information or by customizing the Site to your particular preference or interests. 

**PAY DQ** may disclose personal information if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on **PAY DQ** or the Site; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of **PAY DQ** and our family of Web sites; or (c) act in urgent circumstances to protect the personal safety of **PAY DQ** employees or agents, users of **PAY DQ** products or services, or members of the public.

Top of page

**Control of Your Personal Information**  
Except as otherwise described in this statement, personal information you provide on the Site will not be shared outside of **PAY DQ** and its controlled subsidiaries and affiliates without your permission. As described below in the next section, you can access your personal information and make choices about how you wish to be contacted.

**PAY DQ**.com may send out periodic e-mails informing you of technical service or security issues related to a product or service you requested, or confirming you requested a product or service. Top of page

**Subscribe or Cancel Subscriptions to Newsletters or Offers**  
You can access your personal information by contacting **PAY DQ**.com as described at the bottom of this statement, or through alternative means of access described by the service. For example, if you are a **PAY DQ** client, you can review and edit your personal information by contacting our National Client Service Manager Monday through Friday, between the hours of 8 a.m. and 5 p.m. CT at 1-888-741-1647 Extension 1000. Top of page

**Security of Your Personal Information**  
**PAY DQ** is committed to protecting the security of your personal information and that of your customers. We use a variety of security technologies and procedures to help protect personal information from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. For example, we store the personal information you provide on computer servers with limited access that are located in controlled facilities. Additionally, when we transmit sensitive personal information (such as a credit card number) over the Internet, we protect it through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol. Top of page

**Use of Cookies**  
We do not use cookies on this Site. A cookie is a small text file that is placed on your hard disk by a Web page server. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies are uniquely assigned to you, and can only be read by a Web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you.

One of the primary purposes of cookies is to provide a convenience feature to save you time. For example, if you personalize a web page, or navigate within a site, a cookie helps the site to recall your specific information on subsequent visits. This simplifies the process of delivering relevant content, eases site navigation, and so on. When you return to the Web site, the information you previously provided can be retrieved, so you can easily use the site's features that you customized.

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of this or other Web sites you visit. Top of page

**Enforcement of this Privacy Statement**  
If you have questions regarding this statement, you should contact **PAY DQ**.com Top of page

**Changes to this Statement**  
We may occasionally update this privacy statement. When we do, we will also revise the "last updated" date at the top of the privacy statement. For material changes to this privacy statement, we will notify you either by placing a prominent notice on the home page of our Web site or by directly sending you a notification. We encourage you to periodically review this privacy statement to stay informed about how we are helping to protect the personal information we collect. Your continued use of the service constitutes your agreement to this privacy statement and any updates. Top of page

**Contact Information**  
**PAY DQ** welcomes your comments regarding this privacy statement. If you believe that **PAY DQ** has not adhered to this privacy statement, please contact us electronically or via postal mail at the address provided below, and we will use commercially reasonable efforts to promptly determine and remedy the problem.

**PAY DQ**.com privacy  
**PAY DQ**  
25 Main Place, Suite 400  
Council Bluffs, Iowa 51503-0970  
Email: [info@paydq.com](mailto:info@paydq.com)  
Top of page
